RG 095, Council on Human Services
Connecticut State Library
Council on Human Services records
1973-1977
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Council on Human Services
6 cubic feet
In 1973, the General Assembly created the Council on Human Services to coordinate planning and carrying out programs involving two or more agencies, to plan for increased private sector participation, and to provide direction to and coordination with federally funded programs. The Council took over administrative responsibility for some existing programs and developed some new ones including Project Triage (home-care for the elderly), the Wilderness School, the Parent Child Resource System, and the Information and Referral Service. In 1976, the General Assembly abolished the Council as an administrative agency, changing its status to that of an advisory body to the Governor. In 1977, the Council was replaced by a human services reorganization commission.
RG095
T002772
Historical Note
In the 1960's there were a number of state government agencies concerned with what have come to be described as human services. The Etherington Commission on reorganization of the state government recommended the creation of a single department. A second study, by the Zimmerman Commission, produced a similar recommendation, but the General Assembly compromised, in 1973, by creating the Council on Human Services to coordinate the planning and carrying out of programs involving two or more agencies, to plan for increased private sector participation, and to provide direction and coordination to federally funded programs. The Council, made up of the heads of the eleven human services agencies and several public members, was headed first by Lt. Governor Peter Cashman and later by Secretary of the State Gloria Schaffer. Its small staff was provided at first by the Planning and Budgeting Division of Finance and Control, one of whose officers, Rosalie Lang, became the Council's Executive Director in the fall of 1974.
The Council took over administrative responsibility for some existing programs and developed some new ones such as: Project Triage (home-care for the elderly), the Wilderness School, the Parent Child Resource System, and the Information and Referral Services, and it also assisted in obtaining federal grants for related programs to be carried on by the other state departments.
At its 1976 session, the General Assembly in effect abolished the Council as an administrative agency, changing its status to that of an advisory body to the Governor and providing for the transfer of its operating functions to other state agencies. At the end of June 1976 the process was practically complete.
Following the Filer Commission report at the end of 1976, the General Assembly enacted a major reorganization plan (P.A. 77-614) which Governor Grasso signed on June 2, 1977. This provided for replacement of the Council by a human services reorganization commission, which was to prepare a new "state human services plan" (Sections 546-548).
See also the.
Scope and Content
Materials include correspondence, meeting minutes and audiotapes, reports, subject files, and reference materials.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Council on Human Services
Persons:
Cashman, Peter; Schaffer, Gloria, 1930-
Subjects:
Human services -- Connecticut; Social service -- Connecticut; Connecticut. Council on Human Services -- Records and correspondence; Public welfare -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Minutes; Reports; Sound recordings; Correspondence
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
These records came to the State Library from the Social Services Department in October 1977 and from the Human Resources Department in January 1979.
Container List
- Records, 1973-1977
  - 1. General file, 1973-1977
    Correspondence, minutes, notes, memoranda, reports, reference materials and transcripts.
    - Administrative memos and decisions (Box 1)
    - (Appropriations) budget - letters (Box 1)
    - Assessment letter, 1976 May 6 (Box 1)
    - Attorney General - rulings and correspondence (Box 1)
    - Blank contract forms (Box 1)
    - Budget - miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Budget submission (FY 1975-1976) (Box 1)
    - Budget submission (FY 1976-1977) (Box 1)
    - Bulletins (Box 1)
    - Capacity Building Toward Coordinated Human Services (Box 1)
      - A-95 (Box 1)
      - Correspondence (Box 1)
      - Original submission superseded, 2 copies (Box 1)
      - HEW - Partnership Grant - Grant Award # 005A-7051-P0122 ($43,000.00), 1975 September 1-1976 August 31 (Box 1)
      - Application materials (Box 1)
      - Grant (Box 1)
      - Implementation (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
      - Monthly reports (Box 1)
      - Staff memos (Box 1)
    - CETA - Contracts (Box 1)
    - CETA - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Information Retrieval Committee "C" MIS confidentiality (Box 1)
    - Committee "C" reports (Box 1)
    - Confidentiality and freedom of information (Box 1)
    - Conn. Assoc. for Community Action (CAFCA) (Box 1)
    - Connecticut Humanities Council (Box 1)
    - Coordinating and other functions of the CHS - prepared for public members (Box 1)
    - Correspondence with the Legislature (Box 1)
    - Correspondence - Misc. (Box 1)
    - Membership opinions (Box 1)
    - List of members (Box 1)
    - Delegated authorizations to act (Box 1)
    - Education - Department of (Box 2)
    - Executive Orders and Administrative Rulings (Box 2)
    - F (Box 2)
    - Finance and Control - Department of (Box 2)
    - Governor's Executive Orders # 3 & 17 (Box 2)
    - Governor's Office - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - HEW - Application blanks, guidelines (Box 2)
    - Health, Education and Welfare - Department of, correspondence and miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - DHEW - General provisions for contract (Box 2)
    - HEW: Project SHARE (Box 2)
    - HEALTH - New Haven Health Care, Inc. (Box 2)
    - HEALTH - Service areas (Box 2)
    - Human Services program survey (Box 2)
    - Information and Referral (Box 2)
      - Articles, reports & background (Box 2)
      - Proposal drafting (Box 2)
      - Regional subcontracts (Box 2)
      - Advisory Board (Box 2)
      - Agreement with CUW (Box 2)
      - Agreement with DSS (Box 2)
      - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 2)
      - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2)
      - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 2)
      - Minutes (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
      - RFP process (Box 2)
      - Technical group (Box 2)
      - Uniform statewide proposal (Box 2)
    - Intergovernmental programs (Box 2)
    - Juvenile Court (Box 2)
    - Juvenile Court (Box 2)
    - Lieutenant Governor Robert K. Killian (Box 2)
    - Lease - Council on Human Services (Box 2)
    - Labor - Department of (Box 2)
    - Legislation - Enabling and proposed (Box 2)
    - Legislation: Federal Privacy Act and Public Disclosure Provisions (Box 2)
    - Legislature - Appropriations Committee (Box 2)
    - Legislature - Fiscal Analysis (Box 2)
    - Legislative history of the CHS (Box 2)
    - Legislation (State) Juvenile Justice (Box 2)
    - Legislature: Public Health and Safety Committee - Subcommittee on Home Health Care (Box 2)
    - Legislation: State Freedom and Information Act (Box 2)
    - Manpower Planning (Box 2)
    - Mailing lists - names and addresses, etc. (Box 2)
    - Minutes from Council on Human Services (Box 3)
      - 1974 November-1975 August (Box 3)
      - 1974 (Box 3)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 3)
      - 1976 February-1977 December (Box 3)
    - Office of Management & Budget (OPM) - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Public members - correspondence with (Box 3)
    - Public Participation Committee (Box 3)
    - Public - private relationships (Box 3)
    - Public support for the CHS (Box 3)
    - CHS - Region I HEW Forward Planning (Box 3)
    - Regional & Sub-State Planning Pilot Project Area B (Box 3)
    - Report to the Governor and Legislature, 1975 January (Box 3)
    - Research criteria (Box 3)
    - Parent-Child Resource System Project - Annual Report, 1974 July 1-1975 June 30 (Box 3)
    - Social Services - Department of (Box 4)
    - Sub-State District Maps (Box 4)
    - Sub-State District Correspondence (Box 4)
    - Secretary of the State - Gloria Schaffer (Box 4)
    - Soc. Sec. Act - Title IV A transfer of family day care (Box 4)
    - Social Security Act - Title XIX Child care - EPSDT (Box 4)
    - Social Security Laws and Regs - Title XIX (Box 4)
    - Status offender (Box 4)
    - Sub-State Districts - January 19, 1976 resolution & follow-up reports re: Gov's request (Box 4)
    - T (Box 4)
    - Title XX (Box 4)
      - Title XX (Box 4)
      - Public Law (93-647) (Box 4)
      - Correspondence (Box 4)
      - Service survey forms (Box 4)
      - Single state agency designation (Box 4)
      - Blank forms (Box 4)
      - DCA (Box 4)
      - Proposed regulations (Box 4)
      - Final regulations, 1975 June 27 (Box 4)
      - Social Services Amendment of 1974 - summaries and discussions (Box 4)
      - Fiscal business (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
      - Planning implementation (Box 4)
    - Transcripts, Council Meetings, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
    - Transcripts, Council Meetings, 1974 (Box 4)
    - Transfer of Psychiatric Services (Box 4)
    - Transfer of Psychiatric Services - Implementation (current) (Box 4)
    - Testimony - CHS, Public (Box 4)
    - Treasury Department, Letters of Credit (Box 4)
    - U (Box 4)
    - UCONN Forum (Box 4)
    - Workmen's Compensation - Booklet State of Connecticut, 1973 (Box 5)
    - CEP Xerox Usage Record Sheets (old) (Box 5)
  - 2. Correspondence, 1974 (Box 5)
    Unarranged and unfiled papers.
  - 3. Tapes of Council meetings, 1973-1974; Dictabelt tapes. (Box 5)
    Presumably some of these are duplicated by transcripts in the General File.
  - 4. General file, 1975-1977 (Box 5)
    Correspondence, minutes, etc.
    - Annual Report, 1975-1976 (Box 5)
    - Agendas (Box 5)
    - Bills (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Filer Report (Box 5)
    - Dept. of Health (Box 5)
    - Public member comments re: Filer Report (Box 5)
    - Legislation (Box 5)
    - Members (Box 6)
    - Public Members - Vitae (Box 6)
    - Dept. of Mental Health (Box 6)
    - Taskforce on the Deaf (Box 6)
    - Information and Referral Services (Box 6)
    - Requests for copies of information (Box 6)
    - Gloria Schaffer - Secretary of State (Box 6)
    - Snoke, Dr. Albert (Box 6)
    - Title XX (Box 6)
    - Speeches (Box 6)
    - Minutes of meetings (Box 6)
    - Work sheets minutes (Box 6)
    - Wilderness School (Box 6)
  - 5. Files on project evaluation of parent-child resources system, 1974-1975 (Box 6)
    Correspondence, reports, contracts, etc.
    Alphabetical by subject.
    - Agreements, contracts and sub-contracts (Box 6)
    - Autism contracts FY 1974-1975 (Box 6)
    - Autism programs & funding (Box 6)
    - Background reports & studies (Box 6)
    - Blank contract forms (Box 6)
    - Budget and audits (Box 6)
    - Correspondence FY 1975 (Box 6)
    - Consortia meeting - minutes/agendas (Box 6)
    - Eastern Conn., PCRS, Inc. - meeting (Box 6)
    - E. Ct. P.C.R.S., Inc. (Box 6)
    - E. Ct. P.C.R.S., Inc. - by-laws (Box 6)
    - Evaluation component (Box 6)
    - Evaluation criteria (Box 6)
    - Fiscal matters (Box 6)
    - Information and referral contracts, 1974 November 1-1975 June 30 (Box 6)
    - Mental Health Services Contracts, 1975 January 2-1975 June 30 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Model contract development (Box 6)
    - Monitoring (Box 6)
    - Problems identified (Box 6)
    - Project staff reports (Box 6)
    - Publicity (Box 6)
    - Regional consortia/articles of association (Box 6)
    - Summaries of descriptions (Box 6)
    - Research contracts FY 1974-1975 (Box 6)
    - Service contracts & subcontracts - active (Box 6)
    - Service contracts & subcontracts - completed (Box 6)
    - Speech hearing and language contract through June 30, 1975 (Box 6)
    - Tech. Advisory Committee (Box 6)